# Hadi Sinaee

## **SUMMARY**

I have an **M.Sc.** in **Computer Science** with **7 years** of **software engineering** experience and expertise in **data structures**, **algorithms**, **and software engineering practices**. I excel in driving technical decisions and managing projects (research/industry). My interests span a wide spectrum of systems areas, including *MLSys*, *SysML*, *Distributed Systems*, *Databases*, and *Operating Systems*.

## **EXPERIENCE**

o Systopia Lab.

### | University of British Columbia

Vancouver, Canada

- Systems Researcher

Jan 2021 – Oct 2023

- · Conducted research on graph processing systems and partitioning algorithms.
- · Developed a graph partitioner that achieved 70% higher quality partitioning than the baseline.

## o Torob Inc. | Intelligent Search Engine For Online Shopping

Tehran, Iran Apr 2020 - Dec 2020

- Sr. Software Engineer | Product Team
   Led Sr. Software Engineers and Designers for a 9M+ user product.
  - · *Implemented* data-driven solutions, cutting user complaints by **30%**.
  - · Devised and Implemented a shop ranking system, boosting click rate by 10%.

#### o Ostadkar.pro | The Largest Marketplace For Home Services in Iran

Tehran, Iran

- Chief Technology Officer

Mar 2019 - Feb 2020

Led cross-functional teams in engineering, product, and data analytics for a 1M+ user marketplace.

- Scaled successfully the technology and product teams by a factor of 5 within 6 months.
- Scaled successibility the technology and product teams by a factor of 5 within 6 mont Led senior interviews, calibrated practices, and shaped hiring initiatives.
- *Led* the successful transition from a monolithic architecture to a microservice-based architecture.
- Sr. Software Engineer

Jul 2018 - Mar 2019

- · Designed and implemented the marketplace software for beauty products.
- · Generated 50% more orders and tripled supplier count.
- · Influenced product decisions/scope, evaluating technical tradeoffs for rapid customer value.

#### HodHod | Messaging Application

Tehran, Iran

- Co-founder and CTO

Jul 2015 – Jul 2018

- · Secured consecutive funding (A, B, C) from top VCs and accelerators.
- · Implemented distributed messaging architecture.
- · Attained 200K+ DAU and 2M+ installs with over 1M users.

#### o Miras Technologies | Big Data Platform

Tehran, Iran

- Data Scientist
- Jun 2015 Jan 2016
  - $\cdot$  Executed end-to-end ML projects for customer classification and weather pollution prediction.
  - · Implemented predictive weather models, providing insights for Tehran Municipality.

## **EDUCATION**

## University of British Columbia

M.Sc. Computer Science, Systems, supervised by Prof. Margo Seltzer

Jan 2021 – Oct 2023

**Sharif University of Technology** 

OM.Sc. Artificial Intelligence (Machine Learning)

Sep 2013 – Feb 2016

University of Kashan

 $^{\circ}$  B.Sc. Software Engineering, ranked  $1^{st}$  in class of 2013

Sep 2009 - Sep 2013

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming**: Go, Python, Java, JavaScript, C/C++, Bash

Technologies: Git, Docker, Kubernetes, gRPC, Kafka, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Redis, Django, Flask,

Apache Parquet, HDFS, etcd, fluentd, Prometheus, Knative, Perf, GDB

Libraries: OpenCV, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, OpenMP, networkx, graphical model learning, PyTorch

Misc.: Gitlab CI/CD